Let’s get some answers to these two situations.
What did you come up with for what line 2 will
print? Line 2 is a slicing statement,
as we have square brackets on the quote,
and the slice starts at character 4 and goes to
character 9. In looking at the quote, I think the
word quick should display, as the q is in position
4, and we are looking to display the next five
characters. We will run this code in a moment.
Regarding the question on line 4 as to what type
of data structure this is, this data structure
is a tuple, as the items in this list are in
parentheses. Sets and dictionaries have items in
curly brackets, and lists have items in square
brackets. The next question is, can we change
the value of platinum to bronze? Technically,
we can, but we cannot do it just by changing a
value, as I am attempting to do here, on line 6,
as tuples are immutable, meaning they cannot be
changed. The only way to make the change is to
redo the tuple, as I will do on line 6, with the
new value. And then I will add a print statement
on line 7 to display the new tuple values. I will
now run the code, and both results display in the
terminal. Knowing how to manipulate lists is a big
time-saver as, just like we saw in creating lists,
being able to group values in a single variable
and then make changes to the group saves one
from having to create and store separate values in
separate variables, which can be tough to manage
given every variable has to have a different name.
Imagine trying to store 50 state capitals and
having to name the variables capital1 through
capital50. That list would be tough to track.